"The Stranger I Met" Episode 14
《我遇见的陌生人》 第14集
(Wu Gang Dumu)
（吴刚杜姆）
(Kyung Gi Joo)
（京基珠）
"A Stranger I Met"
《我遇见的一个陌生人》
What happened in the village...
村里发生的事……
I found the defendants in those cases
我在那些案件中找到了被告
He saw himself killing someone
他看见自己杀人了
my brother
我的兄弟
(Excerpted from previous episodes)
（摘自前几集）
- I finally got this guy. - Ma'am.
- 我终于抓住这个家伙了 - 女士
The culprit is not Wuguang
罪魁祸首不是五光
Not the defendant, but the witness
不是被告，而是证人
The defendant is a male
被告是一名男性
The only person who recognizes his face is Hou Guang
唯一认得他脸的人就是 后光
- Mr. Yin - Mr. Liu Fan
- 尹先生 - 柳范先生
sunshine air
阳光空气
it won't happen
它不会发生
Li Sheng'er, hurry up
李升儿快点
mr san el
桑埃尔先生
Another person died
又一个人死了
This time it's a student
这次是一名学生
A good boy died in an abandoned house
一个好男孩 死在废弃的房子里
Otherwise, Li Sheng'e will die.
不然李升娥就死了
If only because of the teacher
如果只是因为老师的话
I almost fell in love with the murderer
我差点就爱上凶手了
(Bangbang Teahouse)
（邦邦茶馆）
how long have you been here?
你来这里多久了？
(I'm glad I remembered and saw you again)
（很高兴我记得， 再次见到你）
(Episode 14: The person who makes you happy)
（第14集：让你幸福的人）
Article (14)
第 (14) 条
(Wujiang Hospital)
（吴江医院）
A bald, disgusting guy.
一个秃头、恶心的家伙
Where do you think you are from?
你认为你来自哪里？
Where did you come from, threatening me with such information ?
你从哪里来的，用这样的信息 威胁我？
I'll see that bald guy's face
我会看到那个秃头家伙的 脸
- Calm down and get up there - Madam.
- 冷静下来，上去 - 女士
shameless
无耻之徒
Yin Yongsheng
尹永升
Let's go to our house now
我们现在去我们家吧
Yes
是的
that crazy guy
那个疯狂的家伙
That guy is not a very bold person
那家伙不是一个很 大胆的人
Have you reached this point and still left threatening letters?
难道都到了这个地步，还留下恐吓信了？
He is not afraid of being caught
他不怕被 抓住
This is...
这是...
Do you think so?
你这样认为吗？
In my opinion this is the complete opposite
在我看来， 这完全相反
This guy is totally scared now because he's afraid of getting caught
这家伙现在彻底害怕了，因为 他害怕被抓住
After any threat
无论如何威胁之后
I need to shut that girl up
我要让那个女孩闭嘴
this is the first time
这是第一次
I couldn't kill anyone
我没能杀死一个人
He was shocked by the fact that the victim was still alive
他对受害者还活着的 事实感到震惊
But why are there only two detectives?
但为什么只有两个侦探呢？
- Well - in this village...
- 嗯 - 在这个村庄...
Is there anything more important than this?
还有比这更重要的事情吗？
When I opened the complaint, why did only two detectives come?
当我打开投诉时， 为什么只有两个侦探来？
That is...
那是...
The police don't want this to become a big deal
警方不希望这件事闹大
This time too
这次也是
Does it make sense for us to go alone ?
我们一个人去 有意义吗？
Even if all the detectives were gone, it wouldn't be enough
即使所有的侦探都走了， 还是不够
The defendant went to the hospital
被告人前往医院
Who says this is the culprit?
谁说这是罪魁祸首？
-What did someone say in this message?
-有人在这条消息中说了什么？
What if I'm kidding?
如果我是在开玩笑怎么办？
Why did you conclude that you were the culprit?
为什么 你会得出你是罪魁祸首的结论？
Go quietly, don't alert people, it's free
安静地走，不要惊动人们，免费
Bring me that little piece of paper right now
马上把那张小纸条 拿给我
I'll do a test, okay?
我会做检查，明白吗？
(Lee Sun-Ah kidnapping case file)
（李善阿尔绑架案档案）
(Bangbang Teahouse)
（邦邦茶馆）
Anyway, what can you do to cause trouble for the boy who was arrested?
不管怎样， 你能做什么来找那个被捕的男孩的麻烦呢？
Don't tell me about the promotion to police chief
别告诉我晋升警察局长的事
Even now, the position is uncertain, so that means he can't give us much time
即使现在，位置还不确定， 所以这意味着他不能给我们太多时间
So what can I do?
那我能做什么呢？
The one who was arrested was Gominsu
被抓的是Gominsu
I have to be the culprit
我必须成为罪魁祸首
Lee Joo-young and Lee Kyung-a were killed by Go Min-soo
李周英和李京娥 被高民秀杀死
The last case is another person's hand
最后一个案例是另一个人的 手
Yes of course
是的当然
If so, we can solve at least one case
如果是的话，我们 至少可以解决一个案例
But although I can't find any evidence of Yu Bum Yong
但尽管我找不到Yu Bum Yong的任何证据
That student, Lee Sun Else, has witnesses.
那个学生，Lee Sun Else， 有证人
same handwriting
一样的笔迹
"Women who read are dangerous "
“读书的女人很危险” 这个
This makes sense if there is no written explanation
如果没有文字说明的话， 这是有道理的
So the note I found in the hospital room today ...
所以我今天在病房里发现的 纸条......
This is something that doesn't exist
这是不存在的东西
(Congratulations on hosting the 1988 Seoul Olympics)
（祝贺举办1988年汉城奥运会）
Thank you very much for sending me, Detective.
非常感谢你派我来， 侦探
It doesn't matter
没关系
So the question tonight
那么今晚的问题
I can't tell anyone right now
此刻 我无法告诉任何人
May interfere with investigation
可能会干扰调查
Do you get me?
你明白我的意思吗 ？
certainly
当然
Detective, arrest the murderer as soon as possible
侦探，尽快逮捕凶手
Yes
是的
Why is this so?
为什么会这样呢？
among those who came to ask for news
在前来询问消息的人中
The defendant may be present
被告可能在场
Who came looking for it?
谁来找它的？
Why don't you ask?
你为什么不问？
this is just a program
这只是一个程序
if you wait
如果你等一下
How long do you have to wait?
你需要等多久？
How do you plan to handle this case?
您打算如何处理此案？
He even received threatening messages from the defendant
他甚至收到了被告发来的威胁信息
Just get it home and that's the end of it, isn't it?
只要把它送回家， 一切就结束了，不是吗？
I'll go to camp and confirm
我会去营地并确认
(The 5th Wujingli Fireworks Festival)
(第五届五井里烟火大会)
(TV prep time)
（电视准备时间）
Where are you going? Why come now?
你要去哪儿？为什么现在才来？
I think I can find a way to face you
我想我能找到一种方式 面对你
Are they inside?
他们在里面吗？
Come in and talk
进来谈谈吧
Is this news?
这是新闻吗？
Yes
是的
What happened last night was included in the news
昨晚发生的事情 被列入新闻
After being discharged from hospital yesterday
昨天出院后
I went around the whole village
我绕遍了整个村子
But neither the villagers nor the police
但无论是村民还是警察
The surroundings were quiet, as if nothing had happened
周围很安静，就像什么都没发生过一样
This silence is not safe for Sun-e
这种沉默对 Sun-e 来说 并不安全
Not only that, he also received threatening messages from the defendant
不仅如此， 他还收到了被告发来的威胁信息
There's not even a police guard in front of this house.
这栋房子门前 连警察都没有看守
Now we need to get as much public involvement in this case as possible
现在 我们需要让公众尽可能多地参与到这个案件中
The police should investigate more actively
警方 应更积极地调查
If the police are unwilling to do this
如果警察 不愿意这样做
we have to make it happen
我们必须让它发生
I think the most accurate way is in the news
我认为最准确的方法是在新闻中
If we identify previous cases
如果我们 确定之前的案例
The police can no longer investigate
警方无法再调查
If the police have started an investigation
如果警方已经开始调查
The defendant will not approach Sun Al easily again.
被告不会再轻易接近孙阿尔
At present, all this is to ensure the safety of Sun Aier
目前，这一切都是为了保证孙艾尔的 安全
I think this is the only way to catch the culprit
我认为这是抓住罪魁祸首的唯一方法
but...
但...
this way
这样做
Shouldn't Son El be in the news herself?
Son El自己不应该 出现在新闻中吗？
The victim's interview went like this
受害人的采访是这样的
I know exactly what you're worried about
我很清楚你在担心什么
face and voice
脸和声音
I have to do this so I don't even remember Sun El
我必须这么做，让我根本不记得Sun El
I know journalists who would do that.
我很了解会这样做的记者
I believe Mr. Yin, but...
我相信尹先生， 但是……
Even if you cover your voice and face like that
即使你像那样遮住声音和脸
No one else knows, but the defendant knows
其他人不知道，但 被告知道
this is about my daughter
这是关于我女儿的
This may be more dangerous
这 可能更危险
To be honest, I don't want to
老实说，我不想
for my teacher
为我的老师
You've never cooked, have you?
你从来没有做过饭，是吗？
I've always wanted to cook it once
我一直想煮一次
Prepared hastily, although there is not much curry
仓促准备的， 虽然咖喱不多
Participation
参加
How was the food?
食物怎么样？
Yes
是的
one way or another
不管怎样
The worst situation
最坏的情况
Even though something as sad as this happened to my child
即使这样悲伤的事情 发生在我的孩子身上
Feed your family no matter what
无论如何都要养活家人
A mother's feelings
一个母亲的感受
Even though Mr. Yin is not my son
尽管尹先生不是我的儿子
I think this is our family
我认为这是我们的家人
if not
如果不
At the same time we
与此同时我们呢
care, think, worry, help
照顾、思考、担心、 帮助
can you do it?
你能做到吗？
As the teacher said, this is other people's business
正如老师所说，这是别人的事
other people's business
别人的事
that's why
这就是为什么
If such a teacher really thinks this information is important
如果这样的老师真的 认为这个信息很重要
i want to believe
我想相信
keep us safe
让我们安全
Can you do the same thing?
你能做同样的事吗？
Miss
女士
You know what the police have told us the most so far?
你知道到目前为止警察告诉我们最多的是什么吗？
"Keep calm and quiet."
“保持冷静，安静。”
Has anyone been able to resolve this issue so far?
到目前为止有人能够解决这个问题吗？
If you do nothing because you are afraid
如果你因为害怕而什么都不 做
we are all here
我们都在这里
How long is he going to hide like this?
他要这样隐藏多久？
I want to do what is reported in the news
我想做新闻里报道的事情
I want to do it too
我也想做
Because it's not me who's wrong
因为错的不是我
he should be afraid
他应该害怕
Because I'm not the culprit
因为我不是罪魁祸首
Although it will be difficult for the family
虽然家人会很困难
This is an important interview, please do it well
这是一次重要的采访， 请好好做好
Good focus shot of mother and daughter
母亲和女儿的良好对焦镜头
- Be sure to wear a press jacket - Yes
- 一定要穿记者夹克 - 是的
Be sure to chew on your face
一定要在脸上咀嚼
The sound must also change radically
声音也必须彻底 改变
The audience wants to know the face of the perpetrator, not the face of the victim.
观众想知道的 是肇事者的面孔，而不是受害者的面孔。
I'm sure
我敢肯定
It would be better if it could be displayed directly
如果能直接展示就更好了
Last night’s matchbox and text message
昨晚的火柴盒和短信
The police have taken it, haven't they?
警察已经拿走了，不是吗？
Yes, everything is imported
是的，一切都已经进口了
Yes I know
是的，我知道
I would start shooting the same way
我也会以同样的方式开始拍摄
Let's start interviewing reporter Gin
让我们开始采访记者Gin吧
what are you doing here?
你在这里做什么？
So what are you doing there ?
那么你在那里 做什么？
(Bangbang Teahouse)
（邦邦茶馆）
What if the case becomes public while the police are still investigating ?
如果在警方仍在调查期间 案件被公之于众怎么办？
without witnesses
没有证人的情况下
Was the witness just smuggled out like this?
证人就 这样被偷偷偷偷带出去了是吗？
Because I don't know when and how the place inside will be destroyed
因为我不知道里面的地方会在什么时候、如何被摧毁
you are right
你是对的
People from the future don't lie
来自未来的人 没有谎言
But we didn't expect things to get that bad
但我们没想到事情会变得那么糟糕
One more thing has really disappeared
还有一件事真的消失了
(Lee Sun-Ah kidnapping case file)
（李善阿尔绑架案档案）
When student Li Shanyi ran away from the abandoned house
当学生李善 一从废弃的房子里逃跑时
The information in my pocket is gone
我口袋里的信息 不见了
You know what this means, right?
你知道这意味着什么，对吗？
That's why you called, right?
这就是你打电话的原因，对吗？
radio reporter
广播电台记者
I would never allow it to be overwritten like this
我绝对不会允许它被这样覆盖
it will still be bubbly
它仍然会很起泡
leader
领导人
- Leader - What?
- 领导 - 什么？
from Seoul Broadcasting Station
来自首尔广播电台
Looks like they're looking into this case everywhere
看起来他们正在到处调查这个案子
Now the whole village is boiling
现在整个村子都沸腾了
Is he a broadcaster from Seoul?
是首尔的广播员吧？
One..Two..Three will start
一..二..三将开始
Rated as a crime-free village for five consecutive years
连续五年 被评为无犯罪村
Yu Zhongjian Yu Zhongyu
宇钟健 宇钟宇
In Wuzhong Village
吴中日村内
There have been three murders in the past 30 days
过去30天内 发生了3起谋杀案
The village will become increasingly noisy
村庄会变得越来越吵闹
The suspect in the brutal murders of two women last May
去年五月残忍杀害两名妇女 的嫌疑人
Each corpse left its own symbol
每具尸体都 留下了自己的符号
One of the text messages was what he wanted to say.
其中一条 是他想说的话的短信
I put it in this matchbox
我把它放进这个火柴盒里
Matchboxes are mostly used by young people in the village
火柴盒 多为村里年轻人使用
Posted from teahouse
从茶馆发布
Based on this information, the police
警方根据这些信息
The defendant often went in and out of ordinary teahouses
被告人经常进出普通茶馆
Assuming it must be a young man from the same village
假设一定是同村的小伙子
The biggest culprit among consumers...
消费者中的罪魁祸首...
Everyone talks about the culprit every day
每个人每天 都会谈论罪魁祸首
Surely the culprit somewhere will see it too
肯定某个地方的罪魁祸首 也会看到它
Because the defendant has not been arrested yet
因为被告尚未被捕
Although the whole village is worried
尽管全村人都担心
Judging from the murder that happened again in s
从s 再次发生的 谋杀案来看
surviving victim
幸存的 受害者
He was reportedly threatened again by the defendant
据报道，他再次受到被告的威胁
The whole village is in panic
全村人心惶惶
when i see this handwriting
当我看到这个字迹时
If you didn't know, the defendant
如果你不知道，被告
I feel like someone is watching me
我感觉有人在旁边看着我
Even so, the police have not taken any action
即便如此，警方 还没有采取任何行动
Is that how it should be?
应该是这样吗？
Our police here
我们警察这边
to protect victims
为了保护受害者
Will try my best to do my best
会尽力做到最好
Things will slowly start to change
情况 将慢慢开始改变
If you see anything suspicious please report it to me
如果您发现任何可疑的情况， 请向我报告
Hello
你好
We will be waiting in front of you 24 hours a day
我们 将24小时在您面前等候
it's sad
这是可悲的
Although it has been a month since the investigation
虽然距离调查已经过去一个月了
no progress?
没有进展？
of course not
当然不
We have arrested the main suspect
我们 已经逮捕了主要嫌疑人
We plan to turn him over to the investigative office as soon as possible
我们计划尽快将他移交给调查办公室
We must change what has not changed
我们必须改变尚未改变的状况
you can stay calm
你可以保持冷静
Either cover up the case
要么掩盖案件
Finally, it looks like they'll make Gominsu the culprit
最后，看来他们会让Gominsu成为罪魁祸首
Anyway, as long as he's caught
无论如何，只要他被捕了
A thorough investigation is impossible
彻底调查是不可能的
As for Hou Guang, hasn’t he said anything yet?
至于后光， 他还没有说什么吗？
what are you talking about?
你到底在说什么？
I've never really lied, detective.
我从来没有真正撒过谎，侦探
Five Flavors Award
五味奖
Do you know how dangerous it is to lie to the police ?
你知道向警察撒谎 有多危险吗？
Even now, if you tell the truth, you pretend not to know your mistake
即使现在，如果你说真话， 你也会假装不知道自己的错误
This is the last chance my uncle gave me
这是叔叔给我的最后一次机会
By the time the real culprit is found it's too late
当找到真正的罪魁祸首时为时已晚
I don't know what crime you would be charged with.
我不知道你会被指控什么样的罪行
I have to call my lonely brother a murderer
我不得不称我孤身一人的兄弟是杀人犯
Do you think it's easy?
你认为这很容易吗？
With the guilt of killing his family
带着杀害家人 的罪孽
Hesitation and thinking countless times every day
每天无数次的 犹豫和思考
He said quite a bit
他说的一点也不少
If you doubt me like this
如果你这样怀疑我
I really found it
我真的找到了
That day, my brother was by the river
那天，哥哥在河边
It seems that Gominsu is not the culprit
看来Gominsu并不是罪魁祸首
if you show evidence
如果你出示证据
I would say I didn't see it
我会说我没有看到
For that kid, this would be a last resort
对于那个孩子来说，这 将是最后的手段
Now I can't wait for his answer
现在我已经等不及他的回答了
The reporter asked more questions
记者越追问
The police will work hard to end this matter as soon as possible
警方将努力尽快结束此事
If we use our method
如果我们使用我们的方法
If you get confession after a few days, you can get
如果几天后得到表白， 就可以得到
No matter how rubbish it is
不管 它多么垃圾
It is impossible to ask her to pay for the crimes she committed
不可能要求她为她所犯下的罪行付出代价
That 's a good thing for the real culprit
这对于真正的罪魁祸首来说 是一件好事
Yuguang didn't even move.
御光连动 都没动一下
How can he rescue his brother?
怎样才能把他的弟弟救出来呢？
acre
英亩
Can I meet him once?
我可以见他一次吗？
(Storage Room)
（储存室）
Because there will be someone guarding the door
因为会有人看守门
Must be completed within 5 minutes
必须在5分钟内完成
Night of the 16th
16号晚上
Do you remember what I encountered?
你还记得我碰见了什么吗？
How do you do it?
你怎么做呢？
I do not love
我不爱
Natale broke his arm
纳塔莱摔断了手臂
I'm trying to get you out of here now
我现在正在努力让你离开这里
Try to remember without thinking
尝试不加思考地 记住
Where was he then and what did he do after that ?
当时他在哪里、之后做了什么 ？
About Li Jing'e
关于李璟娥
Will you tell the police?
你会告诉警察吗？
that night
那晚
your hand is hurt
你的手受伤了
How is it treated?
是如何治疗的？
Does gomisu help?
戈米苏有帮助吗？
Mitsu?
美津？
Miss
女士
ha
哈
He's dying of thirst
他快渴死了
Go buy something to drink
去买点喝的
go
去
Take a taxi
乘坐出租车
I think I went to the hospital
我想我去医院了
sometimes i feel sleepy
有时我感到困倦
Where did he go?
他去哪了？
Mitsu will know
美津会知道的
Every...
每个...
(List of Yu Jongjian taxi drivers)
(宇钟健出租车司机名单)
Lapa
拉帕
I'm tired
我累了
The caller just now was Detective Shi Badong.
刚才打来电话的 是施巴东警探
Starting from the night of the 16th
从16号晚上开始
It was not until the morning of the 17th that it was fully loaded with passengers.
直到17日早上才 满载乘客
Yes
是的
Is it them?
是他们吗？
This is Go Min-soo, who the police say is the main suspect
这是高珉洙，警方称他是主要嫌疑人
alibi
不在场证明
(discharge certificate)
（出院证明）
(Medical Certificate)
（医疗证书）
Miss
女士
No matter how well-informed you are, where did you get this information?
不管你的消息多么灵通， 你是从哪里得到这些信息的？
Is she really a Korean teacher?
真的是韩国老师吧？
The image is not
图像不是
Look like people in our field
看起来像我们这个领域的人
How many minutes do you think it will be when it airs ?
你认为播出时会是多少分钟 ？
To be honest, at first I thought it would take me a minute and a half
说实话，一开始 我以为我会花一分半钟
But when I looked at it, it was only three and five minutes.
但我一看，才 三分钟五分钟
I'm more greedy because I think that's not all I'm seeing now
我更贪婪， 因为我认为这并不是我现在所看到的全部
How about 20 minutes ?
那么20分钟 怎么样？
20 minutes?
20分钟吧？
Mr. Yin seems not sure about the news
尹先生好像不太确定这个消息
have a certain form
有一定的形式
If you present a case for 20 minutes, people...
如果你陈述一个案例 20 分钟， 人们...
Will they get bored?
他们会感到无聊吗？
Although I'm not sure
虽然我不确定
I want to see a detailed presentation of news announcements
我想看详细的新闻公告演示
there will be an audience
会有观众
Reporters are all greedy to do this kind of thing
记者 都有贪心做这种事
Hey, isn't this what you've always wanted to do?
嘿，这不是你一直 想做的事吗？
Shows only two 20-minute popular news stories
仅呈现两则时长为 20 分钟的热门新闻报道
Yes, but how could I do such a thing...
是啊，但是 我怎么能做这样的事呢……
If you force yourself, it will happen
如果你强迫自己，它就会发生
May I?
可以吗？
I think it'll be fine
我想会没事的
The working environment for broadcasters just got better
广播公司的工作环境 变得更好了
My time was really bad.
我那个时代真的很糟糕
in 1989
1989年
Weekend news every 20 minutes
周末新闻每20分钟
They will select two stories and conduct a detailed news announcement presentation
他们将选择两个故事并 进行详细的新闻公告演示
When I was little I said they had to do this
当我还很小的时候，我 就说过他们必须这样做
Aren't you tired of saying that in my day ?
在我这个时代， 你不厌倦这样说吗？
Hey, do you know how groundbreaking this was in our broadcast history?
嘿，你知道这在我们的广播史上有多么开创性吗？
this boy
这个男孩
Can someone please clarify who wrote this history?
有人可以澄清谁写了这段历史吗？
This is what a news anchor should be like
新闻主播就应该这样
Clear, not diminished at all
清晰，一点 也不减少
This guy is cool
这家伙很酷
can i do it?
我可以做吗？
This will be a true pioneer
这将是一个 真正的先驱
Yes, is it?
是的，是吗？
tell the director
告诉导演
The name is used for the fake image
该名称是用于假冒的图像
I will be hospitalized from the night of the 16th to the 18th
我从16号晚上到18号 住院
If this is true, there is no way Gominsu is a murderer
如果这是真的的话，Gominsu 根本不可能是杀人犯
It's absolutely impossible to be sure
绝对不可能确定
reporter
记者
I have to end my turn
我必须结束回合
The main suspect is currently under police investigation
目前 主要嫌疑人正在警方调查中
Arrested Ge Minsu
被捕的戈敏苏
We have evidence that he had an alibi on the day of the incident
我们有证据表明他在事发当天有不在场证据
I'll shoot as soon as the leader comes out
领导一出来我就开枪
come out and shoot
出来射击
- Can I be interviewed by the leader? - I don't mind.
- 我可以接受领导采访吗 - 不介意
Does the main suspect Goss really have an alibi?
主要嫌疑人戈斯真的 有不在场证据吗？
how do you know?
你怎么知道？
So where will the next investigation go?
那么接下来的调查 将会走向何方呢？
Are there any other suspects?
还有其他嫌疑人吗？
Villagers strengthen security in surrounding areas
村民 加强周边治安
The program is now being requested...
现在正在请求该计划...
Responsible police investigation
通过警方负责任的调查
Restore the confidence of Wujingli villagers
恢复五井里村民的信心
I think the villagers' suspicion can be dispelled.
我看村民的怀疑 是可以打消的
What
什么
Why?
为什么？
Can I come in for a moment?
我可以进来一会儿吗？
- Hey, he's back - Yes
- 哎回来了 - 是的
i will come soon
我会很快来
Misu
米苏
What are you doing standing there ?
你站在那里做什么 ？
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
He Wuguang
何五光
Who is this?
这是谁？
Nice to meet you, long time no see
很高兴见到你， 好久不见
What are you doing Did you forget to make an appointment to meet me today?
你在做什么？你忘了今天约了我来见吗？
What, the two of them are close now?
怎么，两人 现在关系亲密了？
Of course convenient
当然方便
they enter together
他们一起进入
Do you want to go back as soon as you are free?
你想一有空就回去吗？
Won't you come?
你不来吗？
I'll go for a while
我去一会儿
Yes, I am confident today
是的，今天我有信心了
I'll see you when I get home
我回家后会见到你
Why help?
为什么要帮忙？
that chain
那条链子
Whenever I feel cold, irritable, or restless
每当我感到寒冷、烦躁、 不安时
The necklace you once held
你曾经握着的那条项链
My habit is to notice it first
我的习惯是先 注意到它
that's why
这就是为什么
Are you OK?
你好吗？
Gominsu is now free
现在 Gominsu 是免费的
Are you crying now?
你现在流泪了吗？
When I see others in pain, I don't exist at all, do I?
当我看到别人痛苦时， 我根本不存在，不是吗？
I don’t know why I’m here on this cold river bank
不知为何就 在这寒冷的河岸边
I also met Mrs. Li who died unjustly...
还遇见了冤死的李太太……
Even if you see your classmates grieving the loss of their sister
即使你看到你的同学 因失去妹妹而悲伤
I'm just trying to use it to your advantage, aren't I?
我只是想用它来为你谋取利益，不是吗？
I did it and now I'm in tears
我做到了，现在我泪流满面
Wait a moment
等一下
I won't care about this
我不会管这个
Is it important?
是不是重要？
Why do girls wear children's clothes?
女孩为何穿着童装？
look ma'am
瞧，女士
Lots of baby clothes and shoes?
很多婴儿衣服和鞋子？
Is it because she's pregnant?
是因为她怀孕了吗？
like mother and son
就像母亲和儿子一样
this
这个
don't throw away
不要扔掉
Throw away the rest
剩下的扔掉
That's cool
这很酷
I also want to know how the case is progressing
我也想知道案件进展如何
I call it anxiety
我称之为焦虑
I heard noises in the village, are you okay?
我听到村子里有声音， 你还好吗？
This is what his grandson did
这是他孙子制造的事情
If I think it's dangerous, I have to stop it
如果我认为这很危险，我就必须阻止它
This person is not free
这个人不自由
What if creating a problem makes people pay attention to him and want to know about him?
如果制造问题能让人们 关注他并想了解他怎么办？
But because of him, many problems have been solved
但因为他，很多问题 都解决了
Student Seon-e is now under police protection
学生Seon-e现已 受到警方保护
And the cases where innocent people were accused of being the culprits stopped there.
而无辜者被指控为罪魁祸首的案件也就此停止了
enough
够了
Now all that's left is for the police to do
现在剩下的就是警察要做的了
Are you listening to me now?
你现在在听我说话吗？
look ma'am
瞧，女士
Lots of baby clothes and shoes?
很多婴儿衣服和鞋子？
Is it because she's pregnant?
是因为她怀孕了吗？
this
这个
don't throw away
不要扔掉
Throw away the rest
剩下的就扔掉吧
This is my grandson
这是我的孙子
Yes
是的
Yes I know
是的，我知道
real
真的
won't get into any more dangerous problems
不会陷入任何更危险的问题
Be quiet, okay?
安静点，好吗？
Yes, I have a help request
是的，我有帮助请求
Well, what do you say?
嗯，你说呢？
Soon Ae was suddenly discharged from the hospital
不久Ae突然出院了
He won't be treated well
他不会得到很好的待遇
I hope he's in a safe place with his family
我希望他能和家人待在安全的地方
Not in this village
不在这个村子里
Even if it's not cold, I'm still worried
即使不冷我也担心
I will look for a good hospital in Seoul
我会在首尔寻找一家好的医院
So do our police
我们的警察也是
- I'll send it there - Okay
- 我会把它发送到那里 - 好吧
and then
进而
Can I use this car for a period of time?
我可以使用这辆车一段时间吗？
Yun Yang
云扬
are you waiting for me?
你在等我吗？
what car is this?
这是什么车？
I'll answer questions as I go
我会边走边回答问题
Anyway, it will take some time
无论如何，还需要一段时间
Why don't you go somewhere?
你为什么不去某个地方呢？
a beautiful place
一个美丽的地方
superior
上
How was the sea in 1987?
1987年的大海怎么样？
It seems clearer
似乎更清楚了
Do you think?
你认为？
I'll come back later to see how it goes
我稍后再回来 看看进展如何
There are many things to confirm
有很多事情需要确认
So I wonder how it got to this point?
那么我想知道它是如何发展到这个地步的呢？
think about it
想一想
take you back in time
带你回到过去
I don’t think I’ve seen any good scenes
我觉得我没 见过好看的场景
After getting the time shuttle car
拿到时光穿梭车后
I think I have also been affected by the times
我想我也受到了时代的影响
Know the time in advance
提前知道时间
I want to change the future
我想改变未来
Because I have to run everywhere
因为我必须到处跑
What I really want to do right now
此刻我真正想做的 事
Who do you want to be, where do you want to be...
你想成为谁、想成为哪里...
I guess I've never thought about these things
我想我从来没有考虑过这些事情
So think about it
所以想一想
Do you want to go see the beautiful scenery with me?
你想和我一起去看美丽的风景吗？
I think so
我想是这样
- Come again Come again
- 再来 再来
in sweet, salty and salty foods that someone likes
在某人喜欢的 甜、咸和咸的食物中
It's like he wants to see how delicious his food is
就好像他想看看他吃的东西有多好吃
again
再次
What do you like and what do you hate?
你喜欢什么，讨厌什么？
I think I'm tired of hearing him say such trivial things.
我想听他说这种鸡毛蒜皮的事听腻了
But I like all the answers
不过我喜欢所有的答案
Let's try each answer
让我们尝试一下每个答案
Excellent
出色地
The best sweet and savory food is topoki
最好的甜咸食物是 topoki
The next round is...
下一个回合是...
used bookstore
旧书店
I also like the smell of old books
我也喜欢旧书的味道
faded yellow pages
褪色的黄页
I also like the feeling of rolling
我也喜欢翻滚的感觉
With old books that are hard to find
带着很难找到的旧书
I also like the feeling of treasure hunting
我也喜欢玩寻宝的感觉
again
再次
Friday 3pm
星期五下午 3 点
3 hours before leaving the office
离开办公室前3小时
It's like owning the whole world
就像拥有了全世界
Do you know this feeling?
你知道这种感觉吗？
Because I was the one who announced the news for the weekend
因为我是之前 宣布周末新闻的人
Oh, who works on weekends?
噢，谁周末工作
So what do you hate about Mondays?
那么你讨厌周一的什么？
Sunday 9pm
周日晚上 9 点
It was from then on that I was no longer confident
正是从那时起， 我不再自信了
Just when I started announcing the news on TV
就在我开始在电视上宣布这个消息的时候
I will love it from now on
从现在开始我会爱上它
This looks like it should be a famous topoki shop in 1987
这看起来应该是1987年的一家著名的topoki店
The rice cakes are chewy and delicious
年糕很有嚼劲， 很好吃
take a bite
咬一口
I also put it in the same game
我也放到同一个游戏里了
I will eat my feast
我会吃我的盛宴
Bus No. 540
公交车 540 路
This is where I sit at the bus stop when I'm depressed
这是我沮丧时 坐在公交车站的地方
I got on the bus and sat there without thinking about anything
我上了公交车， 什么也没想就坐在那里
looking out the window
看着窗外
I feel good after pulling the thread
拉完线后 感觉很好
on the bus
在公交车上
Route 540 has the best scenery
540路 风景最好
i must remember
我必须记住
and then...
进而...
I stop here
我停在这里
just because i tried
只是因为我尝试过
Now really...
现在真的...
I want to hear what you say to me
我想听听你对我说的话
Isn't that why you brought me here?
这不是你带我来这里的原因吗？
The case is not over yet
案件还没有结束
There's no way I was called here for no reason.
不可能无缘无故地被叫到这里
Why did you get to this point and because of how difficult it was?
为什么你会走到这一步，因为它有多困难？
no matter what i do
无论我做什么
You'll believe me, won't you?
你会相信我的，不是吗？
What's wrong?
怎么了？
Although I can't tell you in detail what I plan to do now
虽然我不能详细告诉你我现在打算做什么
I can guarantee that nothing will happen
我可以保证什么都不会发生
So don't worry and wait
所以不用担心并等待
(Bangbang Teahouse)
（邦邦茶馆）
(Finally closed)
（终于关闭了）
Are you leaving now?
你现在要离开吗？
Excellent
出色地
Yes?
是的？
Ho...
嗬……
Can you take me to the bus station?
你能送我去汽车站吗？
I'm a little scared because it's dark
我有点害怕，因为天黑了
I shot the whole village for the news.
为了新闻 我向整个村子开枪了
This is what you reported
这就是你举报的
I heard you 're providing information to reporters
我听说你 正在向记者提供信息
everyone is talking about it
每个人都在谈论它
It's not just your case
不只是你的情况
Are not you afraid?
你不害怕吗？
Because this is just my situation
因为这只是我的情况
It means I live in the village where the murderer walked
意思就是我住在凶手走过的村子里
It feels like the people around me are always in danger
感觉我周围的人 总是很危险
I have too many people to protect
我 有太多的人要保护
good guy
好人
But your mother doesn't think so
但你妈妈 不会这么想
Did I interfere again?
我又干涉了吗？
Sorry, that's it...
对不起，就这样……
If my son did something dangerous to protect someone
如果我的儿子 为了保护某人做了危险的事
I guess I'm worried
我想我很担心
It's like you didn't ask what you think
就好像你 没有问你怎么看
I know, I'm sorry
我知道，对不起
It's like I 'm thinking a lot of these thoughts right now
就好像我现在 正在思考很多这样的想法
(Wuzhuang Grocery Store)
(五庄杂货店)
Why are you holding it?
你为什么拿着它？
baby in my belly
我肚子里的宝宝
I collected every one for him
我收集了每一个给他
There are also homemade ones
也有自制的
Some of them are bought because they look good.
有一些是因为好看所以买的
Are these shoes really cute?
这双鞋真的可爱吗？
How can it be so small?
怎么可以这么小呢？
even in my days
即使在我的日子里
It's really weird to think that you're going to be walking on it
想到你要骑着它走路 真的很奇怪
Such a collection
那样的收藏
Isn’t this what those who are waiting for children do?
这不正是那些苦苦等待孩子的人所做的吗？
I'm waiting
我在等待
Even the name has been given
连名字都已经给了
The "encounter" John and the "happy" John.
“相遇”的约翰和 “幸福”的约翰。
If you meet him he will make you happy
如果你见到他，他会让你开心
Heejun
熙俊
Are you surprised to see the same name?
看到同一个名字你有没有感到惊讶呢？
Me too
我也是
It means it will break
意思就是会断掉
I really want to see
我真的很想看看
my precious children and my loved ones
我的宝贝孩子和我所爱的人
Such a child
这样的孩子
If you look at me with sparkling eyes
如果你用闪闪发光的眼睛 看着我
how beautiful
多么美丽啊
I've had this thought
我已经有过这样的想法
Why are you leaving?
你为什么要离开？
Now I'm not sure
现在我不确定
want to go
要去
thank you for sending
感谢您发送
so?
所以？
This is good
这很好
("KSBC Nine Hour News")
（《KSBC九小时新闻》）
"KSBC Nine O'Clock News" will be broadcast soon
《KSBC九点新闻》 即将开播
Our news today is very special
今天我们的新闻很特别
Unlike the original model, there are only two cases
与原来的型号不同，只有两种情况
will present
将呈现
Each case is divided into two parts
每个案例分为两部分
A detailed investigation was carried out
对此进行了详细调查
The first case has appeared for five consecutive years
首例已连续五年出现
It was chosen as a crime-free village
它被选为无犯罪村庄
It tells the story of a serial murder case that happened in a village ...
讲述了发生在一个村庄的 连环杀人案……
- Hey - Yeah
- 嘿 - 嗯
Is this the news coming from our village ?
这就是我们村里传来的消息 吧？
Yes, that's the one who left the message in the matchbox
是的，就是那个在火柴盒里 留言的人
Miss
女士
(City bus ticket office at Wujingri)
（市内公交车 乌泾日售票处）
Become a crime-free village for five consecutive years
连续五年成为无犯罪村
Selected
被选中
Goi-ri, Goi-gun, Goi- gun Village
五井里五井郡五井 郡村内
There have been three murders in the past 30 days
过去30天内 发生了3起谋杀案
The suspect in the brutal murders of two women last May
去年五月残忍杀害两名妇女 的嫌疑人
Each corpse left its own symbol
每具尸体都 留下了自己的符号
One of the text messages was what he wanted to say.
其中一条 是他想说的话的短信
I put it in this matchbox
我把它放进这个火柴盒里
Matchboxes are mostly used by young people in the village
火柴盒 多为村里年轻人使用
Posted from teahouse
从茶馆发布
Based on this information, the police
警方根据这些信息
The defendant had been in and out of ordinary residences
被告曾进出普通住宅
Assuming it must be a young man from the same village
假设一定是同村的小伙子
Are there any suspects among consumers who may be the culprit?
消费者中 是否存在嫌疑人可能是罪魁祸首
Although I made some inquiries
虽然我做了一些询问
No obvious results yet
还没有明显的结果
Because the defendant has not been arrested yet
因为被告尚未被捕
Although the whole village is worried
尽管全村人都担心
It happened again
事情又发生在
Murder survivor
谋杀案中幸存的 受害者
He was reportedly threatened again by the defendant
据报道，他再次受到被告的威胁
The whole village is in panic
全村人心惶惶
when i see this handwriting
当我看到这个字迹时
If I didn't know better, I would feel like the defendant was right next to me, watching me
如果我不知道的话，我会觉得被告 就在我身边看着我
she is a terrible person
她是一个可怕的人
that's what i said
这就是我所说的
Are they really from our village?
真的是我们村的人吗？
- Well - in order to restore the trust of the villagers in Wujingli...
- 嗯 -为了恢复五井里村民的信任..
Aren't you here now?
你现在不在吗？
my mom says some disgusting things
我妈妈说一些令人厌恶的话
How quiet is this village ?
这个村子有多 安静？
- It's possible - Yes
- 有可能 - 是的
- Don't say things like that - No.
- 不要说这样的话 - 不
Reporters are currently investigating
目前记者 正在调查中
private visit
私人访问
I'll look at the witness statements
我会看看证人的证词
Witnesses being interviewed now , other than survivor witnesses
现在接受采访的目击者 除了幸存者目击者之外
as additional witness
作为补充证人
It may be important to arrest the accused
逮捕被告可能很重要
He gave me important news
他给了我重要消息
I hope the audience will pay attention and listen.
希望观众关注、倾听
Well
唔
I teach Korean literature at Gojing High School
我在五井高中 教韩国文学
This is Yoon Hyejun
这是尹慧俊
I came on the night of the 4th
我是4号晚上的
A third murder occurred in this abandoned house.
这座废弃的房子里发生了 第三起谋杀案
He is also a witness
他也是目击者
At that time, he followed the defendant
当时，他跟随被告
Then he ran to the mountains
然后他跑到山上
Has the teacher interviewed you?
老师面试了吗？
He told me he would bite me in the face
他告诉我他会咬我的脸
Why does the teacher show his face?
老师为什么要 露脸？
as i see
正如我所见
The defendant was wearing a black hat and black jacket
被告戴着黑色帽子，身穿 黑色夹克
There is a vertical tear on the back.
背面 有一道垂直撕裂
Is it because of the teacher’s face?
是因为老师那张脸吗？
That is, other people have already got everything
也就是说，其他人 已经得到了一切
- Why teacher... - That's what I said
- 为什么老师... - 我就是这么说的
brother
兄弟
- Bro - Okay
- 兄弟 - 好吧
What are you so focused on ?
你这么专注做什么 ？
It's a bit like this...
有点像这样...
angry
生气的
So in the end , I don't know if there's anything else to say.
所以最后 我不知道还有什么要说的吗
During the pursuit of the defendant
在追捕被告人的过程中
I saw the defendant's face with my own eyes
我亲眼看到了被告的脸
If you confront the defendant again
如果您再次与被告对峙
I think you can remember it
我想你一定能记住
Send it out to Oh Jae-ri, Gyeonggi-do as soon as possible
尽快送出京畿道吴在里
Yes
是的
Both houses are now empty
现在两栋房子都空了
If you wait until tomorrow night you'll get it
如果你等到明天晚上， 你就会得到它
Did he really show up?
他真的出现了吗？
If he watches the news, it will definitely appear
如果他看新闻， 肯定会出现
It was hard to control the urge to see what he said he saw on his face
很难控制想要看到他所说的在他脸上看到的东西的冲动
What
什么
Why are you here?
你为什么来这里？
What was said in the news...
新闻里说了什么...
He saw the defendant's face
他看到了被告的脸
It's a lie, isn't it?
这是一个谎言，不是吗？
what did he say?
他说什么？
So what if the real culprit is found?
如果找到真正的罪魁祸首又如何？
Why do you do such a dangerous thing ...
为什么要做这么危险的事 ...
Let's leave here for now
我们暂时离开这里吧
how do you know?
你怎么知道？
this is a lie
这是一个谎言
I can't see his face
我看不到他的脸
how do you know?
你怎么知道？
How can you be so sure?
你怎么能这么肯定？
if you find
如果你找到了
Because there is no reason to know
因为没有理由知道
Absolutely...
绝对地...
There is no reason to say such a thing
没有理由说这样的话
did you know?
你可知道？
Who is the culprit?
罪魁祸首到底是谁？
In that box of baby supplies
那个盒子里的婴儿用品里
This one also exists
这个也有
When will that child be born?
那个孩子什么时候出生
cold winter wind
寒冷的冬风
I want to put warm clothes on for him
我想给他穿暖和的衣服
I do it by myself
我自己做的
acre...
英亩...
Do you know what this is?
你知道这是什么吗？
It's all my stuff
都是我的东西
The ropes that bind those people
束缚那些人的绳索
matchbox
火柴盒
everything starts from me
一切都从我开始
Our Xizhong
我们的熙中
I really want to meet this kid
我真的很想见见这个孩子
But now I don't know what to do
但现在我不知道该怎么做
he...
他...
That bad guy...
那个坏人...
that person...
那个人...
The child's father...
孩子的父亲..
Are you talking about the culprit?
你说的是罪魁祸首吗？
Is that why you left?
这就是你离开的原因吗？
I am afraid
我害怕
Because it's so disgusting
因为它太恶心了
Because I can't stay with people like this anymore
因为我不能再留在这样的人身边了
I have been waiting for this child for a long time...
这个孩子我等了好久了..
I do not know right now
我现在不知道
Now I don't want to see it again
现在我不想再看到它
Now...
现在...
I don't want to see it again
我不想再看到它了
That man’s child is…
那个男人的孩子是……
Very disgusting
非常恶心
I'm afraid
我耽心
Why did he...
为什么他...
Why this...
为什么这个...
Hare
野兔
Yunyunwu
云云吴
"A Stranger I Met"
《我遇见的一个陌生人》